kvraudio.com 2019-06-13

# KVR: Privacy

KVR Audio ("KVR", "our", "we", "us") is owned and operated by KVR Audio, Inc.

KVR Audio, Inc.  
PO Box 620323  
Woodside, CA 94062.  
USA.

If you wish to contact KVR Audio, Inc. regarding any aspect of this Privacy Policy our data protection officer can be reached at contactus@kvraudio.com.

* * *

KVR Audio respects individuals' right to privacy. KVR Audio will never use your personal data for any use beyond that stated or the permissions you give us or as required by law. This Privacy Policy aims to give you information on how KVR Audio collects and processes your personal data when you use [www.kvraudio.com](https://www.kvraudio.com/) ("Website"). The information that you provide us with, or that is gathered automatically, helps us and third parties to monitor our service and provide you with the services that you have subscribed to.

* * *

## **1.0 Personally Identifiable Information**

Our definition of personally identifiable information includes any information that may be used to specifically identify or contact you, such as your name, email address, mailing address, phone number, etc. Unless you create a [KVR Audio User Account](https://www.kvraudio.com/register) we do not automatically collect your personally identifiable information when you visit our Website.

### **1.1 General**

To perform many of the functions on this website such as posting in our forum, submitting comments below new items, product listings, etc., subscribing to newsletters, update notifications, etc., purchasing in the KVR Marketplace (online store), etc. requires that you have a KVR Audio User Account and are logged in to that account. A user account is created by the user by entering an email address and choosing a username and password at <https://www.kvraudio.com/register>. The email address must be confirmed and the account activated by clicking a link in the initial email sent to the supplied email address.

Initially, the email address is the only personally identifiable information that KVR Audio stores. The username you choose may also be classed as personally identifiable if you choose something that resembles your name, band, organisation, company, etc.

All references to a user's email address in this document refer to that email address associated with the user's KVR Audio User Account. We do not store email addresses separate from the user's account (for example, we do not use a third party mailing list service).

Please note that your password is ciphered (a one-way hash) so that it is secure. However, it is recommended that you do not reuse the same password across a number of different websites. Your password is the means of accessing your account at KVR, so please guard it carefully and under no circumstance will anyone affiliated with KVR or another 3rd party legitimately ask you for your password. Should you forget the password for your account, you can use the "[I forgot my password](https://www.kvraudio.com/forum/ucp.php?mode=sendpassword)" feature to generate a new one. This process will ask you to submit your e-mail address, then the software will generate a new password, send it to your email address whereupon you must click a link to activate it to reclaim your account.

### **1.2 Children's Privacy**

You must be 16 years of age or older to create a KVR Audio User Account. However, we allow individuals under the age of 16 to utilise our website, but they may do so only with the involvement, supervision, and approval of a parent or legal guardian.

We do not knowingly seek or collect personal information from or about children without the explicit consent of a parent or guardian.

If we become aware that personal information that has been submitted to us relates to a child without the consent of a parent or guardian, we will use reasonable efforts to:

  * Delete that personal information from our files as soon as possible.
  * Ensure, where deletion is not possible, that this personal information is not used further for any purpose, nor disclosed further to any third-party.

Any parent or guardian with queries and questions concerning personal data processing that may relate to their child should contact us via email to contactus@kvraudio.com.

### 1.3 KVR Audio Forum & Discussion / Comments Sections

Should you choose to add a post in our forum or other comment / discussion sections (such as below news items, product listings, etc.), the username of your logged in KVR Audio User Account will be displayed on the post / comment and your computer's IP address and the time and date that you submitted the comment will be logged in our database (accessible only to KVR administrators and KVR Moderators where appropriate and necessary). This information is used to identify you as a contributor to the comment section of the respective page, post or forum and is not passed on to any third party data processors. Only your username will be shown on the public-facing website.

Your comment and its associated personal data will remain on this site until we see fit to either remove the comment or remove the forum post. Should you wish to have a comment and its associated personal data deleted, please [email us here](mailto:contactus@kvraudio.com?subject=KVR%20post%20comment%20removal) using the email address that you commented with and an explanation as to why you would like it to be removed.

If you are under 16 years of age you **MUST** obtain parental consent before posting a comment or forum post on KVR Audio.

_**NOTE** : You should avoid entering personally identifiable information into the actual comment / post field of any comments or forum topics that you submit on this website. You must also avoid posting the personal information about any other people. _

### **1.4 KVR Marketplace**

If you make a purchase via the [KVR Marketplace](https://www.kvraudio.com/marketplace/) ([www.kvraudio.com/marketplace](https://www.kvraudio.com/marketplace/)) you must also supply further personally identifiable information, such as full name and address, to facilitate the purchase process. We share appropriate details with our payment processor to process your credit or debit card or invoice your PayPal account. Your information may also be accessible to the developer or representative of the product(s) purchased if they have been given administrative access to that developer account at KVR Audio - they may use this information for after-sales contact and support. We do not share this information with any other third party. We do not store payment card numbers apart from the final 4 digits.

### **1.5 Giveaways & Promotions**

KVR Audio runs regular giveaways for software products in association with third parties. These opt-in promotions require the user to agree to each giveaways's Terms & Conditions at the time of entry where they agree to share their name and email address with the third party (i.e. the company providing the prize for the giveaway).

### **1.6 Email Newsletters**

If you choose to join any of our email newsletters, the email address from your KVR Audio User Account will be used until you specifically request removal from the list. You can do this by unsubscribing using the one-click unsubscribe links contained in any email newsletters that we send to you or by [requesting removal via email](mailto:contactus@kvraudio.com?subject=KVR%20Audio%20Newsletter%20Unsubscribe) or by modifying your subscriptions at <https://www.kvraudio.com/optin.php>. When requesting removal via email, please send your email to us using the email account that is subscribed to the mailing list (i.e. the one associated with your KVR Audio User Account).

Our newsletters may contain promotions or advertisements from various businesses or information on other sites or services that we offer.

If you are under 16 years of age you **MUST** obtain parental consent before joining our email newsletters.

### **1.7 KVR Learn**

The [KVR Learn](https://www.kvraudio.com/learn/) section ([www.kvraudio.com/learn](https://www.kvraudio.com/learn/)) is offered in partnership with NonLinear Educating Inc. to deliver a high quality training and learning experience using their extensive range of popular video courses. KVR Learn has its own additional [Terms Of Service](https://www.kvraudio.com/learn/?nleloc=terms-of-service) and [Privacy Policy](https://www.kvraudio.com/learn/?nleloc=privacy-policy) which you must read and agree with before you make a purchase there.

## **2.0 Non-Personal Information**

Our definition of non-personal information is any information that does not personally identify you. Non-personal information can include certain personally identifiable information that has been de-identified; that is, information that has been rendered anonymous. We and/or our third party service providers may obtain non-personal information about you from information that you provide us, either separately or together with your personally identifiable information. We and/or our third party service providers may also automatically collect certain non-personal information from you when you access our Websites.

### **2.1 Cookies**

By browsing and interacting with our Website our server software will create a number of cookies, which are small text files that are downloaded on to your computer's web browser temporary files. The primary cookie contains a user identifier and an anonymous session identifier, automatically assigned to you by the Website software, and is essential to enable the user to log in and remain logged in to the Website. Another cookie will be created once you have browsed topics within KVR and is used to store which topics have been read, thereby improving your user experience. Additional cookies may be set to remember user preferences for some site features such as interface style choices.

You may delete all cookies set by the KVR server by clicking this link: <https://www.kvraudio.com/forum/ucp.php?mode=delete_cookies>

Additional cookies associated with website analytics and advertising may also be set on your computer - see sections 2.3 and 3.0 below.

You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can modify your settings to decline cookies as well as delete existing cookies from your device if you prefer. If you choose to decline and/or delete cookies, you may not be able to use all features of the KVR Audio website that depend on cookies (including logging in).

### **2.2 Server Logs**

KVR Audio may collect your IP address to produce a server log – as all web servers do. This information is used solely for monitoring the volume of traffic the site receives and measuring the number of readers. We do not use the information for tracking the activities of specific visitors to the Website.

### 2.3 Site Visitation Tracking

Like many websites, this site uses Google Analytics (GA) to track user interaction. We use this data to determine the number of people using our site, to better understand how they find and use our web pages and to see their journey through the website.

Although GA records data such as your geographical location, device, Internet browser and operating system, none of this information personally identifies you to us. GA also records your computer's IP address which could be used to personally identify you but Google do not grant us access to this.

GA makes use of cookies, details of which can be found on [Google's developer guides](https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/analyticsjs/cookie-usage). Our website uses the analytics.js implementation of GA.

Disabling cookies on your Internet browser will stop GA from tracking any part of your visit to pages within this website.

## **3.0 Advertising & Affiliates**

The KVR Audio website is free to use but it is funded by advertising. Consequently, we run adverts using third-party advertising servers. These ad servers may attempt to set cookies on your computer. All these sites stress that information gathered through these cookies is used purely for the purpose of advert delivery, recording and segmentation. They do not use information gathered through their cookies for their own use, and they do not collect any personally identifiable information.

We use [Google Doubleclick for Publishers](https://www.google.com/dfp) and [Google AdSense](https://www.google.com/adsense) to deliver banner advertising - they are configured to show _non-personalized ads_. Our website also contains some affiliate marketing links, which means we get paid commission on sales of those products or services we or our members write about or link to. Our editorial content is not influenced by advertisers or affiliate partnerships. We use a 3rd Party, [Skimlinks](http://skimlinks.com/), to enable these affiliate partnerships automatically.

Important links:

## 4.0 Data

### **4.1 Data retention**

We will only retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements.

You may, at any time, request that we correct personal data that we hold about you which you believe is incorrect or inaccurate. You may also ask us to erase personal data if you do not believe that we need to continue retaining it. We are not always obliged to erase personal data when asked to do so; if for any reason we believe that we have a good legal reason to continue processing personal data that you ask us to erase we will tell you what that reason is at the time we respond to your request.

In some circumstances we may anonymize your personal data (so that it can no longer be associated with you) for research or statistical purposes in which case we may use this information indefinitely without further notice to you.

### **4.2 Data storage and security**

We use encryption (SSL) to protect your personal data when appropriate, and all the information provided to KVR Audio is stored securely once we receive it.

### **4.3 Data Breaches**

We will report any unlawful data breach of this website's database or the database (s) of any of our third party data processors to any and all relevant persons and authorities within 72 hours of the breach if it is apparent that personal data stored in an identifiable manner has been stolen.

## **5.0 Changes to our privacy policy**

This privacy policy may change from time to time inline with legislation or industry developments. We will not explicitly inform our clients or website users of these changes. Instead, we recommend that you check this page occasionally for any policy changes.

_Last updated - January, 2019_
